WILL IRVINE

London UK | willirvine@yahoo.co.uk | indigo2000.co.uk | linkedIn: will-irvine-12675a236 | github: indigo2000 | CodeSignal: indigo2000

Professional Summary

With over 2 years of experience as a software developer, I have worked on projects that enhanced system efficiency. Holding an MSc in Computer Science, I specialise in Python and Java, contributing to projects that improved performance. Currently learning JavaScript and React, I focus on detail and professionalism, ensuring optimal system uptime. I strive to continuously improve and seek practical solutions to challenges, driving successful outcomes.

Skills

- Python
- React
- JavaScript
- Java
- C
- C++
- Git
- Large Language Models

- LangChain
- SQL
- HTML
- CSS
- Azure
- APIs
- Algorithms and Data Structures

Work Experience

Key Stage and Technology Coordinator | Teacher of Mathematics Kingsdale Foundation School

04/2015 to Current London UK

- Revamped lesson plans for students in Years 9 and 10, leading to improvements in overall performance.
- Integrated technology into the classroom, increasing student engagement through the effective use of digital tools.
- Mentored trainee teachers, enhancing their teaching practices and classroom management skills.
- Delivered Mathematics instruction to students aged 11-18, with a strong record of students exceeding their target grades.
- Monitored student progress and implemented targeted strategies to maximize academic success.

Functional Skills Coordinator

09/2007 to 04/2015

London UK

St. Michael's Catholic College

- Led the integration of Numeracy Across the Curriculum, improving student skills.
- Created new A-level Mathematics schemes and resources, enhancing student achievement.
- Mentored trainee teachers, ensuring success in teaching assessments.
- Taught students aged 11 to 18, with strong record of student success against target grades.
- Developed strategies that boosted student engagement in Mathematics.

Teacher of Mathematics 09/2004 to 08/2007
Shirley High School Croydon UK

- Taught Mathematics to students aged 11 to 16, adjusting lessons for different abilities and learning styles.
- Simplified complex topics, improving student comprehension.
- Adapted teaching methods to help students show progress in key areas.
- Formulated engaging lessons, increasing participation.
- Supported students of all abilities, with many progressing toward their target grades.

Analyst Programmer 03/2001 to 11/2001
Netvoyager PLC London UK

- Developed an operating system for a thin client using C/C++ in Linux, improving system efficiency.
- Created a web browser with TCL for a set-top box, boosting browser speed.
- Responsible for overall build of thin client operating system.
- Worked with teams in web browser development, improving performance.
- Embraced team cohesion to strive for success in a small start-up.

Design/Development Engineer

10/1999 to 10/2000

McLennan Servo Supplies Ltd.

MSc: Computer Science

Surrey UK

12/2024

- Implemented hardware and embedded software in C/C++ (on an FPGA) for a valve controller used in nuclear power stations across Europe, reducing response time.
- Designed software in C/C++ to assist in the labelling of cables destined for the Airbus A380 for BAE systems, improving performance.
- Developed meticulous system testing procedures, ensuring reliability.
- Wrote product specifications, test specifications and manuals.
- Commissioned systems dealing directly with customers and on-site queries..

Education

University of York
PGCE: Mathematics 11-18
Institute of Education
B.Eng: Electronic Engineering (Hons)

York, UK
07/2004
London, UK
07/1999

University of York York, UK

A-Levels and GCSEs: 06/1996
Eltham College London, UK

A-Levels: Mathematics, Music, Physics GCSEs: 10 including Maths and English.

Certifications

CodeSignal Certified, Codesignal, Revisiting Software Design Patterns in Python, 20/02/25 CodeSignal Certified, Codesignal, Advanced Built-In Data Structures and their Usage, 02/02/25 Microsoft Certified, Microsoft, Azure Fundamentals, AZ-900, 05/01/23

Extra-Curricular

IT | At Home

Honed skills in Python to control hardware from LEDs to robots using a Raspberry Pi and a BBC micro:bit. Also implemented mods in Minecraft using Python.

Football | Goals, Beckenham

Manage and play in weekly 6-a-side football matches.

Music | Global

Written, recorded and produced music, arranging for its international release. Also achieved grade VII with distinction on the Tuba and won the Brass Prize at school.